Only his passion for women could rival his passion for painting.
Surviving Picasso is a drama, romance film directed by James Ivory.
The passionate Merchant-Ivory drama tells the story of Francoise Gilot, the only lover of Pablo
Picasso who was strong enough to withstand his ferocious cruelty and move on with her life.
Pablo Picasso, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Françoise Gilot, played by Natascha McElhone.
Dora Maar, played by Julianne Moore.
Henri Matisse, played by Joss Ackland.
Françoise's Grandmother, played by Joan Plowright.
Kootz, played by Dennis Boutsikaris.
Surviving Picasso is a 1996 American biographical drama film directed by James Ivory
and starring Anthony Hopkins as the famous painter Pablo Picasso.
It was produced by Ismail Merchant and David L.
Ruth Prawer Jhabvala's screenplay was loosely based on the 1988 biography
Picasso: Creator and Destroyer by Arianna Stassinopoulos Huffington.
The film explores themes of infidelity, france,
paris, france, love triangle, pregnancy.
The tone is emotional.